today we will talk about how to apply
今天我们将讨论如何申请
the methods of deep learning to
深度学习的方法
understanding the sense of the human
理解人的意识
being the focus will be on computer
重点将放在计算机上
vision the visual aspects of a human
视觉是人类的视觉方面
being
存在
of course we humans express ourselves
当然，我们人类表达自己
visually but also through audio voice
视觉上也通过音频语音
and through text beautiful poetry and
并通过文本美丽的诗歌和
novels and so on we're not going to
小说等我们不会去
touch those today we're just going to
触摸今天我们要去的那些
focus on computer vision how we can use
专注于计算机视觉我们如何 使用
computer vision to extract useful
计算机视觉提取有用
actionable information from video images
来自视频图像的可操作信息
video of human beings in particular in
特别是人类的视频
the context of the car so what are the
汽车的背景是什么的
requirements for successfully applying
成功申请的要求
deep learning methods in the real world
现实世界中的深度学习方法
so when we're talking about human
所以当我们谈论人类的时候
sensing we're not talking about a basic
感觉我们不是在谈论一个基本的
face recognition of celebrity images
面对 名人形象的 认可
we're talking about using computer
我们在谈论使用电脑
vision deep learning methods to create
愿景深度学习方法创造
systems that operate in the real world
在 现实世界 中 运作的系统
and in order for them to operate in the
而为了 让他们 在 工作
real world there are several things they
现实世界中有 几件事
sound simple some are much harder than
听起来简单有些比硬得多
they sound first and the most important
他们听起来是第一位也是最重要的
here for most to less more to less
这里的大多数 要少到更少
critical ordered is data data is
关键排序是数据数据
everything real world data we need a lot
我们需要的一切真实世界数据
of real world data to form the data set
用于形成数据集 的现实世界 数据
on which these supervised learning
这些监督学习
methods can be trained I'll say this
方法可以训练 我会说这个
over and over throughout the day today
一整天都在 一遍 又一遍
data is everything that means data
数据是 指数据的 一切
collection is the hardest part and the
收藏是最难的部分和
most important part we'll talk about how
最重要的部分 我们将谈论如何
that data collection is carried out here
数据收集 在 这里进行
in our group at MIT all the different
我们在麻省理工学院的小组 都有所不同
ways to capture human beings in the
捕捉人类的方法
driving context in the road user context
在道路用户环境中驾驶环境
pedestrians cyclists but the data it
行人骑自行车但是数据呢
starts and ends at data the fun stuff is
有趣的东西 是 数据的开始和结束
the algorithms but the data is what
算法但数据是 什么
makes it all work real world data okay
使所有工作 真实的 世界数据 没关系
then once you have the data okay data
一旦你有数据好的数据
isn't everything I lied because you have
不是我撒谎的 一切， 因为 你有
to actually annotate it so what do we
实际上注释它所以我们做 什么
mean by data there's raw data video
数据是指原始数据视频
audio lidar all the types of sensors
音响激光雷达所有类型的传感器
we'll talk about to capture real world
我们将谈论捕捉 现实世界
you wrote user interaction you have to
你写了你必须的用户互动
reduce that into meaningful
将其减少为有意义的
representative cases of what happens in
发生了什么事的代表性案例
that real world in driving 99% of the
真正的世界 在驾驶99％的
time driving looks the same it's the
时间驾驶看起来是一样的
it's the 1% the interesting cases that
这是有趣案例的1％
we're interested in and what we want is
我们感兴趣并且想要的是什么
algorithm to train learning algorithms
训练学习算法的算法
on those 1% so we have to collect 100
在那1％所以我们必须收集 100
percent we have to collect all the data
百分之我们 要 收集所有 数据
and then figure out and automated
然后弄清楚 并自动化
semi-automated ways to find the pieces
找到碎片的半自动方式
of that data that could be used to train
那些可用于训练的数据
your own networks and that a
自己的网络 和 一个
representative of the general thing
代表性的一般事物
kinds of things that happen in this
发生在 这里的各种事情
world efficient annotation annotation
世界有效的注释注释
isn't just about drawing bounding boxes
不只是绘制边界框
on images of cats annotation tooling is
关于猫注释工具的图像是
key to unlocking real world performance
解锁现实世界表现的关键
systems that successfully solve some
成功解决一些问题的系统
problem accomplish some goal in real
问题在实际中完成了一些目标
world data that means designing
世界数据意味着设计
annotation tools for a particular task
特定任务的注释工具
annotation tools that are used for
用于的注释工具
glance classification for determining
扫视分类确定
where drivers are looking it's very
司机们 正在寻找它
different than annotation tools used for
比用于注释工具不同
body pose estimation is very different
身体姿势估计是非常不同的
than the tooling use that we use for
而不是我们使用的工具用途
psyche views investing thousands of
投资数千心理意见
dollars for the competition for this
为此竞争的美元
class to annotate fully scene
用于注释完整 场景的类
segmentation where every pixel is
每个像素所在的分割
colored there's needs to be tooling for
颜色有需要为工具
each one of those elements and they're
这些元素中的每一个都是
key that's HCI question that's a design
关键是HCI问题是一个设计
question there's no deep learning
问题没有深刻的学习
there's no robotics in that question
那个问题没有机器人技术
it's how do we leverage human
这是我们如何利用人类
computation human the human brain to mow
计算人类人类大脑要 割草
effectively label images such that we
有效地标记图像，使我们
can train y'all networks on them
可以训练你们所有的网络
hardware in order to train these
硬件， 以培训这些
networks in order to parse the data we
网络，以解析 我们 的 数据
collect and we'll talk about we have now
收集， 我们现在谈论我们
over five billion images of data of
超过50亿 的数据图像
driving data in order to parse that you
驱动数据以便解析你
can't do it on a single machine you have
你不能在一台 机器上做到这一点
to do large-scale distributed compute
做大规模的分布式计算
and large-scale distributed storage and
和大规模的分布式存储和
finally the the stuff that's the most
最后的东西是最多的
exciting that people that there's this
令人兴奋的是，那就是这个
class and many classes and much of the
类和多类而远 之
literature is focused on is the
文学的重点是
algorithms the deep learning algorithms
算法深度学习算法
the machine learning algorithms the
机器学习算法
algorithms that learn from data of
从数据中学习的算法
course that's really exciting and
当然这真的很令人兴奋
important but what we find time and time
重要但我们找时间和时间
again in real world systems is that as
在现实世界系统中再次如此
long as these algorithms learn from data
只要 这些算法从数据中学习
so as long as this deep learning the
所以只要 深入学习就可以 了
data is what's much more important of
数据是更重要的
course it's nice for the algorithms to
当然这 对算法 来说 很好
be calibration free meaning they learn
无校准意味着他们学习
to calibrate self calibrate we don't
校准自校准我们没有
need to have the sensors in an exact
需要准确的传感器
same position every time that's a very
同样的岗位上 ，这是一个很 长的时间
nice feature the robustness of the
不错的 功能 的 稳健性
system is then generalizable across
系统然后 在 普及
multiple multiple vehicles and multiple
多个多车辆和多个
scenarios and one of the key things that
方案和 关键事情之一
comes up time again time and time again
再次 出现的时间 一次又一次
and we'll mention today is a lot of the
我们今天要提的是很多
algorithms developed in deep learning
深度学习中开发的算法
are really focused for computer vision
真正专注于计算机视觉
are focused on single images now the
现在专注于单个图像
real world is happens in both space and
现实世界在空间 和 空间都有发生
time and we have to have algorithms that
时间，我们必须 有算法
both capture the visual characteristics
两者都捕捉 视觉特征
but also look at the sequence of images
还要看一下图像序列
sequence of those digital
那些 数字的 序列
characteristics that form the temporal
形成时间的特征
dynamics the physics of this world so
动态这个 世界的物理学所以
it's nice when those algorithms are able
当这些算法能够实现时，这很好
to capture the physics of the scene
捕捉 场景 的物理特征
the big takeaway I would like if you
如果 你 愿意，我想要的是一个很大的收获
leave with anything today
今天什么都离开
unfortunately it's that the painful
不幸的是，这是痛苦的
boring stuff of collecting data of
无聊的收集数据 的东西
cleaning that data of annotating that
清理那些 注释的 数据
data in order to create successful
数据才能创造 成功
systems is much more important than good
系统比好的重要得多
algorithms or great algorithms it's
它的算法或优秀的算法
important to have good algorithms as
拥有良好的算法非常重要
long as you have neural networks that
只要你有神经网络
learn from that data okay so today I'll
从这些数据中学习好，所以今天我会
talk I like to talk about human
谈我喜欢谈论 人
imperfections and the various detection
不完美 和各种检测
problems the pedestrian body pose glance
问题行人身体姿态一览
and motion cognitive load estimation
和运动认知负荷估计
that we can use to help those humans as
我们可以用来帮助那些人类
they operate in the driving context and
他们在驾驶 背景 和操作
finally try to continue with the idea of
终于尝试继续这个想法 了
the vision that fully autonomous
完全自主的愿景
vehicles as some of our guest speakers
作为我们的一些演讲嘉宾的车辆
have spoke about and sterling anis will
已经谈到了， 并且 将会出现 英镑
speak about tomorrow is really far away
谈及明天是真正远离
that the humans will be an integral part
人类将成为不可或缺的一部分
of the operating cooperating with the AI
与AI合作的运营
systems and I will continue on on that
系统， 我将继续这样做
line of thought to try to motivate why
的思路 ，试图激发为什么
we need to continuously approach the
我们需要不断接近
autonomous vehicle the self-driving car
自动驾驶 汽车
paradigm in the human centered way okay
范式以人为中心的方式 好吧
first before we talk about human
在 我们谈论人类 之前
imperfections let's just pause and
不完美让我们暂停一下
acknowledge that humans are amazing
承认人类是惊人的
we're actually really good at a lot of
我们实际上是 在大量 的 真不错
things that's sometimes sort of fun to
有时候有趣的事情
talk about how much called terrible of
谈论多少叫做可怕的
drivers who are how distracted we are
我们是多么分心的司机
how irrational we are but we're actually
我们是多么不合理，但实际上我们是
really damn good at driving here's a
真的该死的擅长 驾驶这里是一个
video of stadia our soccer player messi
视频的 体育场 我们的足球运动员 梅西
the best soccer player in the world
最好的足球运动员在世界
obviously and the state-of-the-art robot
显然和最先进的 机器人
on the right same thing
在同样的事情上
well there's it's not playing but I
好吧，它不是在播放，但我
assure you the American Ninja Warrior
向你保证美国忍者战士
Casey is is uh is far superior to the
凯西 是呃远远优于
DARPA humanoid robotics systems shown on
显示DARPA人形机器人系统
the right okay so continuing and the
正确的好 了，继续和
line of thought to challenge to
挑战的思路
challenge us here that humans are
在这里挑战我们人类
amazing is you know there's record high
太棒了，你 知道它有创纪录的高度
in 2016 in the United States there was
2016年在美国有
over forty thousand since uh many years
四万因为 呃多年
it's across the forty thousand
这是四万多
fatalities mark more than forty thousand
死亡人数 超过四万
people died in car crashes in the United
人们在美国的车祸中丧生
States but that's in three point two
国家， 但这是三点二
trillion miles traveled so that's one
万亿英里旅行， 所以这是一个
fatality per eighty million miles that's
每八千万英里的死亡率
one in 625 chance of dying in a car
六分之一的机会死在车里
crash in your lifetime interesting side
在你的一生有趣的一面崩溃
fact for anyone in the United States
对于美国的任何人来说都是如此
folks who live in Massachusetts are the
住在 马萨诸塞州的 人是
least likely to die in a car crash
最有可能在一场车祸中死亡
Montana is the most likely so for every
蒙大拿州是 最有可能因此对于每
one that thinks of Boston drives is
一个想到波士顿驾驶的人是
terrible maybe that adds some
可怕的可能会增加一些
perspective here's a visualization of
这里透视图的的可视化
ways data across a period of a day
一天中的数据方式
showing you the rich blood of the city
向您展示城市的丰富血液
that the the traffic flow of the city
那个城市的交通流量
the people getting from A to B and a
人们 从A到B和 a
mass scale and doing it surviving doing
大规模的规模，让它 幸存下来
it okay humans are amazing but they're
没关系，人类是惊人的，但他们是
also flawed texting sources of
也有缺陷的短信来源
distraction with a smartphone the eating
用智能手机分心吃
the secondary tasks of talking to other
与他人交谈的次要任务
passengers grooming reading using
乘客梳理阅读使用
navigation system yes sometimes watching
导航系统是有时候看
video and manually adjusting or
视频和手动调整或
adjusting the radio and 3,000 people
调整收音机和 3000人
were killed and 400,000 were injured in
他们 被杀，40万人受伤
motor vehicle crashes vaulted involving
机动车撞毁涉及的
distraction
娱乐
in 2014 distraction is a it's a very
在2014年分心是一个非常
serious issue for safety texting every
安全短信的严重问题
day more and more people text
一天越来越多的人发 短信
smartphones are proliferating our
智能手机正在激增我们
society 170 billion text messages are
社会170条十亿条短信 是
sent in the United States every month
每月寄往美国
that's in 2014 you can only imagine what
那是在2014年你 只能 想象什么
it is today
它是今天
eyes off road for five seconds is the
眼睛越野五秒钟是
average time your eyes off the road
平均时间你的眼睛离开了
while texting five seconds if you're
如果你 发短信 五秒钟的 话
traveling 55 miles an hour in that five
这 五个人 每小时55英里
seconds that's enough time to cover the
几秒钟就足够了
length of a football field
足球场的长度
so you're blindfolded you're not looking
所以你被蒙上眼睛， 你不是在寻找
at the road in five seconds the average
平均在五秒钟的路上
time of texting you're covering the
你正在发短信的时间
entire football field eight so many
整个足球场 八个 这么多
things can happen in that moment of time
事情可能发生在那个 时刻
that's distraction drunk driving 31% of
这是分散醉酒驾驶的31％
traffic fatalities involve a drunk
交通事故死亡人数 涉及醉酒
driver drunk driving 23% of nighttime
司机醉酒驾驶 23％ 的夜间
drivers tested positive for a legal
司机测试为 合法的 正面
prescription or over-the-counter
处方药或非处方药
medication distracted driving as I said
正如我所说，药物分散了驾驶注意力
is a huge safety risk drowsy driving
是一个巨大的安全风险昏昏欲睡的驾驶
people driving tired nearly three
人们 开车累了差不多三个
percent of all traffic fatalities
所有交通事故死亡人数的百分比
involve a drowsy driver if you are
如果你是一个昏昏欲睡的司机
uncomfortable with videos that involve
对涉及的视频感到不舒服
risk I urge you to look away these are
风险我劝你把 目光移开这些 都是
videos collected by Triple A of
Triple A 收集的视频
teenagers a very large-scale
青少年规模很大
naturalistic driving data set and it's
自然驾驶数据集和它的
capturing clips of teenagers being
捕捉青少年的剪辑
distracted on their smartphone
在他们的智能手机上分心
[Music]
[音乐]
once you take it in the problem we're
一旦你把它解决了我们 的 问题
against
反对
so in the cutting
所以在切割中
context of human imperfections we have
我们所拥有的人类不完美的背景
to ask ourselves is the human centered
要问自己是以人为本
approach to autonomy in systems
系统中的自治方法
autonomous vehicles that are using
正在使用的自动驾驶汽车
artificial intelligence to aid the
人工智能 帮助
driving task do we want to go as I
驾驶任务我们想要 像我一样去
mentioned a couple of lectures ago the
提到几个 讲座 前
human centered way or the full autonomy
以人为本的方式 或完全 自治
way the tempting path is towards full
诱人的道路朝向满满的方式
autonomy where we removed this imperfect
自治，我们删除了这个不完美的
flawed human from the picture altogether
图片中完全有缺陷的人
and focus on the robotics problem of
并专注于机器人问题
perception and control and planning and
感知 和控制与规划
driving policy or do we work together
推动政策或我们一起工作
human and machine to improve the safety
人和机器提高安全性
to alleviate distraction to bring drive
减轻分心带来的驱动力
our attention back to the road and use
我们的注意力回到了道路和使用上
artificial intelligence to increase
人工智能增加
safety through collaboration human robot
通过协作人机器人的安全
interaction versus removing the human
互动与消除人类
completely from the picture as I've
完全不是我的照片
mentioned as as sterling will certainly
提到英镑肯定会
talk about tomorrow and and rightfully
说说 明天是理所当然
so and yesterday or on Tuesday Emilio
所以，昨天或周二 埃米利奥
has talked about the elf four-way is
曾谈到精灵 四向 是
grounded in literature it's grounded in
它 以文学 为基础，以此 为基础
common sense since in some sense it's
从某种意义上讲，它是常识
you can count on the fact that humans
你可以依靠人类的事实
the the natural flaws of human beings to
人类的自然缺陷
over trust to misbehave to be irrational
过分信任行为不当是非理性的
about their risk estimates will result
关于他们的风险估计将导致
in improper use of the technology and
在不正当使用的技术和
that leads to what I've showed before
这导致 了 我之前展示的内容
the public perception of what drivers do
公众对 司机做 什么的看法
and semi autonomous vehicles they begin
他们开始和半自动驾驶汽车
to over trust the moment the system
过度信任系统的那一刻
works well they begin to over trust they
效果很好， 他们 开始过度信任他们
begin to do stuff they're not supposed
开始做他们不 应该做的事情
to be doing in the car taking it for
在车里做它
granted a recent video that somebody
有人 给 了最近的视频
posted this is a common sort of more
发布这 是一种常见的更多
practical concern that people have is
人们所 拥有的实际关注 点
while the traditional ways to ensure the
而传统的方法，以确保
physical engagement of the driver is by
驾驶员的 身体参与 是通过
saying they should touch the wheel the
说他们应该触摸方向盘
the steering wheel every once in a while
方向盘每隔一段时间
and of course there's ways to buy
当然还有买的方法
the need to touch the steering wheel
需要触摸 方向盘
some people hang objects like I can off
有些人像我一样可以挂掉物品
of the steering wheel in this case
在这种情况下 的 方向盘
brilliantly I have to say they shove an
我不得不说他们推了一个
orange into the into the wheel to make
橙色进入车轮制造
the touch sensor fire and therefore be
触摸传感器起火，因此
able to take their hands off the
能够脱手了
autopilot and that that kind of idea
自动驾驶仪 和那种想法
makes us believe that there's no way
使我们相信 ，有 没有办法
that you know humans will find a way to
你知道人类会找到一条路
misuse this technology however I believe
然而，我 相信滥用这项技术
that that's not giving the technology
这不是技术
enough credit artificial intelligence
足够的信用人工智能
systems if are they're able to perceive
系统是否能够感知到
the human being are also able to work
人类也能够工作
with the human being and that's what I'd
和人类在一起， 这就是我的意思
like to talk about today teaching cars
喜欢谈论 今天 教 车
to perceive the human being and it all
感知人类和所有人
starts with data it's all about data as
从数据开始， 它都是关于数据的
I mentioned data is everything in these
我提到数据就是这些中的一切
real world systems with the MIT
与麻省理工学院的现实世界系统
naturalistic driving data set of 25
自然驾驶数据集25
vehicles of which 25 and 21 and equipped
车辆有25 和 21并配备
with Tesla autopilot we instrument them
我们用特斯拉自动驾驶仪测量它们
this is what we do the data collection
这就是我们做数据收集的方法
two cameras on the driver will see the
驾驶员 上 的 两个摄像头 将会看到
cameras on the face capturing
脸上捕捉的相机
high-definition video of the face that's
这是面对高清视频
where we get the glance classification
在哪里我们得到一瞥分类
the emotion recognition cognitive load
情绪识别认知负荷
everything coming from the face that we
一切都来自 我们 的脸
have another camera or a fisheye that's
有另一个相机或 鱼眼
looking at the body of the driver and
看着司机的身体和
that from that comes the body pose
那就是身体姿势
estimation hands on wheel activity
估计手轮活动
recognition and then one video looking
识别，然后一个视频看
out for the full scene segmentation for
为了完整的场景分割
all the scene perception tasks and
所有场景感知任务和
everything is being recorded
一切都在被记录下来
synchronized together with GPS with
与GPS同步
audio with all the can covered from the
所有从覆盖可以将音频
car on a single device synchronization
汽车在单个设备上同步
of this data is critical so that's one
这些数据至关重要，因此只有一个
road trip in the data where thousands
数千人的公路旅行
like it traveling hundreds of miles
喜欢它旅行数百英里
sometimes hundreds of miles under
有时数百英里以下
automated control and autopilot that's
自动控制和自动驾驶仪
the data
数据
again as I said data is everything and
再次，因为我说数据是一切和
from this data we can both gain
从这些数据中我们都可以获益
understanding what people do which is
了解人们做了什么
really important to understand how
了解如何非常重要
autonomy successful autonomy can be
自治成功的自治可以
deployed in the real world and to design
部署在现实世界中并进行 设计
algorithms as for training for training
训练培训算法
the deep learning the deep neural
深入学习 深层神经
networks in order to perform the
网络，以执行
perception tasks better twenty five
感知任务更好 二十五
beagles 21 Tesla's Model S Model X and
比格斯21 特斯拉的模型S模型X和
now model three over a thousand miles
现在模型 三千里
collected a day every single day we have
收集了一天，每一天 ，我们 有
thousands of miles in the Boston
在波士顿数千英里
Massachusetts area driving around all of
马萨诸塞州地区四处奔走
that video being recorded now over five
该 视频 目前 正在录制 过五
billion video frames there are several
十亿个视频帧有几个
ways to look at autonomy one of the big
方式 来看待 自主大的一个
ones is safety that's what everybody
每个人都是安全的
talks about how do we make these things
谈谈我们如何制作这些东西
safe but the other one is enjoyment do
安全，但另一个是享受
people actually want to use it it we can
人们实际上想要尽我们所能
create a perfectly safe system we can
我们可以创造一个完全安全的系统
create it right now we've had it for
现在，我们已经 受 够 了 为创建
ever before even cars a car that never
甚至在汽车之前从未有过汽车
moves is a perfectly safe system well
移动是一个非常安全的系统
not perfectly but almost and but it
虽然并不完美， 但差不多
doesn't provide a service that's
不提供服务，是
valuable it doesn't provide an enjoyable
有价值的， 它不提供愉快
driving experience so okay what about
驾驶体验那么好吧怎么样
slow moving vehicles that's an open
缓慢移动的车辆 是开放的
question the reality is with these Tesla
质疑 这些 特斯拉 的现实
vehicles and l2 systems doing automated
车辆和l2系统做自动化
driving people are driving 33% of miles
驾驶人员驾驶33％的里程
using Tesla autopilot what does that
使用特斯拉自动驾驶仪是什么做的
mean that means that people are getting
意味着这意味着 人们正在获得
value from it they a large fraction of
它的价值很大一部分
their driving is done an automated way
他们的驾驶是以自动方式完成的
that's value that's enjoyment the glance
这是享受一瞥的价值
suffocation algorithm we'll talk about
我们将讨论窒息算法
today is used as one example that we use
今天 被用作 我们使用的 一个例子
to understand what's in this data shown
了解所显示的数据中的内容
with the bar graphs there and the red
用条形图和红色
and the blue red is during manual
手动时，蓝色红色
driving blues during autopilot driving
在自动驾驶仪驾驶期间驾驶蓝调
and we look at glance classification
我们看一眼分类
regions of where drivers are looking on
司机正在寻找的地区
road and off-road and if that
道路和越野，如果那样
distribution changes with automated
分配随自动化而变化
driving or manual driving and would
驾驶或手动驾驶
these glass classification methods we
这些玻璃分类方法我们
can determine that there's not much
可以确定没有多少
difference at least until you dig into
差异 至少直到你深入研究
the details which we haven't done and
我们还没有做过的细节
the aggregate there's not a significant
总计没有重要意义
difference that means people are getting
区别这 意味着人们 越来越
value enjoying using these technologies
使用这些技术享受的价值
but yet they're staying attentive or at
但他们仍然保持专注或在
least not attentive but physically
至少不是细心而是身体上的
engaged when your eyes are on the road
当你的眼睛 在 路上 时，你 会订婚
you might not be attentive but you're at
你可能 不会注意但是你在
the very least physically your body's
至少 在身体上是你的身体
position in such a way your head is
以这样的方式定位你的头脑
looking at the forward roadway that
看着前方的道路
you're physically in position to be
你身体健康
alert and to take in the forward roadway
提醒并接收前方道路
so they're using it and they don't over
所以他们正在使用它并且它们没有结束
trust it and that's I think the sweet
相信它，我觉得这很甜蜜
spot that human-robot interaction needs
认为 人机交互需要
to achieve is the human gaining through
实现是人类获得通过
experience through exploration through
通过勘探经验， 通过
trial and error exploring and
试错和探索
understanding the limitation of the
理解的局限性
system to a degree that over trust can
系统达到 过度 信任 的程度
occur that seems to be happening in this
发生在这似乎正在发生
system and using the computer vision
系统 和使用 计算机 视觉
methods I'll talk about we can continue
方法我会谈到我们 可以继续
to explore how that can be achieved in
探讨如何能够 在实现
other systems when the when the when the
当其他系统何时何时出现
fraction of automated driving increases
自动驾驶的比例增加
from 30% to 40% to 50% and so on it's
从30％到40％到50％等等
all
所有
about the data and I'll I'll harp on
关于数据，我会帮我
this again the algorithms are
这又是算法
interesting you know I will mention of
有趣的你知道我会提到 的
course it's the same convolution neural
当然它是相同的卷积神经
networks it's the same networks that
网络就是那个网络
take in raw pixels and extract features
获取原始像素并提取特征
of interest it's 3d convolutional neural
感兴趣的是它的三维卷积神经
networks that take into sequences of
采取序列的网络
images and extract the temporal dynamics
图像并提取时间动态
along with the visual characteristic for
沿着与视觉特性
the individual images it's RN and
个人 形象 是RN 和
zoella's TMS that use the convolutional
使用卷积的动物园的TMS
neural networks to extract features and
神经网络提取 特征和
over time look at the dynamics and the
随着时间的推移看动态和
images these are pretty basic
图像非常基本
architecture is the same kind of deep
建筑是同样的深刻
neural network architectures but they
神经网络架构，但他们
rely fundamentally and deeply on the
从根本上深深依赖
data on real-world data so let's start
关于真实世界数据的数据，让我们开始吧
where perhaps on the human sensing side
也许在人类感知方面
it all began which is pedestrian
一切都从行人开始了
detection decades ago to put it in con
在几十年前检测到将它置于con
texe pedestrian detection here shown
这里显示的texe行人检测
from left to right on the left is green
从左到右左边是绿色
showing the easier human sensing tasks
显示更容易的人体感知任务
tasks of sensing some aspect to a human
向人类感知某些方面的任务
being but as for your detection which is
但至于 你的检测是什么
detecting the full body of a human being
检测人的全身
in an image or video is one of the
在图像或视频中是其中之一
easier computer vision tasks and on the
更轻松的计算机视觉任务和
right under in the red microcircuits
在红色微电路的正下方
these are the tremors of the eye or
这些是眼睛或眼睛的震颤
measuring the pupil diameter or
测量瞳孔直径或
measuring the cognitive load or the fine
测量认知负荷或罚款
blink dynamics of the eye the velocity
眨眼动态的眼睛速度
of the blink micro glances and I pose
眨眼间微微一瞥， 我摆出姿势
are much harder problems
是更难的问题
so you think body pose estimation
所以你认为身体姿势估计
pedestrian detection phase
行人检测阶段
classification detection recognition
分类检测识别
head pose estimation all those are
头部姿势估计所有这些
easier tasks anything that starts
任何开始的任务
getting smaller looking at the eye and
越来越小看着眼睛和
everything that start getting
一切都开始得到
fine-grained there's much more difficult
细粒度更难
so we start at the easiest pedestrian
所以我们从最简单的行人开始
detection and as the usual challenges of
检测和作为通常的挑战
all of computer vision we've talked
我们谈过的所有计算机视觉
about as the various styles of
关于各种风格
appearance so the inter class variation
外观所以班级变异
the different possible articulations
不同的可能的关节
of put it of our bodies superseded only
的把它放在 我们唯一的替代机构
perhaps by cats but as humans are pretty
可能是猫，但 人类很 漂亮
flexible as well the presence of
灵活以及存在
occlusion from the accessories that we
闭塞我们的配件
wear to occluding self occlusion and
穿戴以阻塞自闭塞和
including each other but that crowded
包括彼此，但拥挤
scenes have a lot of humans in them and
场景中有很多人
they include each other and therefore to
他们包括彼此，因此
be able to disambiguate to figure out
能够消除歧义以弄清楚
each individual pedestrians is a very
每个行人都是非常的
challenging problem so how do people
挑战性的问题所以人们如何
approach this problem well there is I
解决这个问题 也有 我
need to extract features from raw pixels
需要从原始像素中提取特征
whether that was hot cascades hog or CNN
无论是 热 级联猪还是CNN
the through the decades the sliding
经过几十年的滑动
window approach was used because the
窗口方法被使用， 因为
pedestrians can be small in an image or
行人在图像中可以很小或
big so there's the problem of scale so
大所以有规模的问题，以便
you use a sliding window to detect where
你 使用滑动窗口来检测在哪里
that pedestrian is you have a classifier
那个行人就是你有一个分类器
that's given a single image such as this
这给了一个单一的形象，如 本
that's you're not you take that classify
那是 你不是 你的分类
you slide across the image to find where
你在图像 上滑动以找到位置
all the pedestrians of scene are so you
现场的所有行人 都是如此
can use non neural network methods or
可以使用非神经网络方法或
you can use convolution neural networks
你可以使用卷积神经网络
for that classifier it's extremely
对于那个分类器来说非常棒
inefficient then came along our CNN fast
效率低下然后我们快速地来到我们的CNN
our CNN fast our CNN these are networks
我们的CNN快速我们的CNN 这些是网络
that as opposed to doing a complete
而不是做一个完整的
sliding window approach are much more
滑动窗口方法更多
intelligent clever about generating the
智能聪明的生成
candidates to consider so as opposed to
考生如此反对
considering every possible position of a
考虑到的每一个可能的位置
window different scales of the window
窗口不同尺度的窗口
they generate more a small subset of
他们生成了更多的一小部分
candidates that are more likely and
考生更有可能和
finally using a CNN classify for those
最后利用CNN归类为 那些
candidates whether there's a pedestrian
候选人是否有行人
or not whether the there's an object of
或不是否有一个对象
interest or not a face or not and using
是否有兴趣或不使用
that maximum suppression because there's
最大限度的抑制，因为有
overlapping bounding boxes to figure out
重叠边界框来弄清楚
what is the most likely bounding box
什么是最有可能的边界框
around this pedestrian around this
围绕着这个行人
object that's our CNN and there's a lot
对象是我们的CNN而且有很多
of variants now with masks our CNN
我们的CNN现在使用面具的变种
really the state-of-the-art localization
真正的最先进的 本地化
Network mask also adds to this on top of
网络掩码 也增加了这一点
the body box also performed segmentation
机身盒也 进行了分割
there's voxel net which does
那里有体素网
three-dimensional and light our data
三维和轻我们的数据
uses localization and point clouds so
使用本地化和点云
it's not just using it to the images but
它不只是用于图像 而是
in 3d but it's it's it's all kind of
在3d 但它就是它的全部
grounded in the our CNN framework ok
扎根于我们的CNN框架确定
data so we have large-scale data
数据因此我们有大规模的数据
collection going on here in Cambridge if
如果在剑桥这里收集的话
you've seen cameras a lidar various
你看过各种各样的激光雷达相机
intersections throughout MIT we're part
麻省理工学院的交叉点我们是其中的一部分
of that so for example here's one of the
例如，这是其中之一
intersections to collecting about 10
收集大约10个交叉点
hours a day instrumenting it with
每天工作几小时
various sensors I'll mention but we see
我会提到各种传感器， 但我们看到了
about 12,000 pedestrians a day across
每天大约12,000名行人
that particular intersection using 4k
使用4k的特定交叉点
cameras using stereo vision cameras 360
使用立体视觉相机的相机360
now the insta 360 which is an 8k 360
现在的insta 360 是一个8k 360
camera gopro lidar various sizes the 64
相机gopro激光雷达 各种尺寸的64
channel of the 6
6的频道
and recording this is where this is the
和记录这就是这是
this is where the data comes from this
这是数据的来源
is from the 360 video this is from the
是来自360的视频来自
lidar data of the same intersection this
这个相同交叉点的激光雷达数据
is for the 4k camcorders pointing at a
适用于指向a的4k摄像机
different intersection and the different
不同的交叉点和不同
than capturing the entire 360 view with
而不是 捕获整个 360 视图
the vehicles approaching in the
车辆在接近
pedestrians making crossing decisions
行人做出交叉决定
this is understanding the negotiation
这是对谈判的理解
that pedestrian is the nonverbal
那个行人是非语言的
negotiation that pedestrians perform and
行人执行的谈判和
choosing to cross or not especially when
选择交叉或不交时尤其是
they're jaywalking and everybody
他们是jaywalking和每个人
jaywalks especially if you're familiar
jaywalks特别是如果你熟悉的话
with this particular intersection
与这个 特殊的交集
there's more Jay walkers than non
还有更多 杰伊步行者比非
jaywalkers it's a fascinating one and so
jaywalkers 它是一个迷人的 等等
we record everything about the driver
我们记录有关司机的一切
and everything about the pedestrians
关于行人的一切
again our CNN this is where it comes in
再次，我们的 CNN 就在这里
is you do Bonney box detection of the
你做 Bonney盒检测了 吗？
pedestrians here are the vehicles as
这里的行人是车辆
well and allows you to convert this raw
好吧， 并允许你转换这个原始
data into hours of pedestrian crossing
数据分为行人过路时间
decisions and begin to interpret it
决定并开始解释它
that's pedestrian detection bounding box
这是行人检测边界框
for body pose estimation is the more
用于身体姿势估计 的更多
difficult task body pose estimation is
困难的任务 身体姿势估计是
also finding the joints the hands the
也找到 了手的关节
elbows the shoulders the hips knees feet
肘部膝盖肘部弯曲
the landmark points in the image XY
图像XY中的标志点
position that marked that those joints
标志着那些关节的位置
that's body pose estimation so why is
这是身体姿势估计所以为什么
that important in driving for example
这在驾驶中很重要
it's it's important to determine the
确定这一点非常重要
vertical position or the alignment of
垂直位置或对齐方式
the driver the seatbelts and the sort of
安全带的司机和那种
the the airbag testing is always
安全气囊测试总是如此
performing the seatbelt testing is
进行 安全带测试
performed with the dummy considering the
与 虚拟考虑进行
frontal position in a standard dummy
标准假人的正面位置
position the the greater greater degrees
定位越大的程度
of automation comes more capability and
自动化带来更多的能力和
flexibility for the driver to get
灵活的 司机赶下车
misaligned from the standard corner
与标准角落不对齐
dummy position and so body pose or at
假位置和身体姿势或在
least upper body pose estimation allows
最小上身姿势估计允许
you to determine how often these drivers
你确定 这些多久驱动程序
get out of line from the standard
从标准中脱离出来
position the general movement and then
定位一般运动然后
you can look at hands on wheel
你可以看看手上的轮子
smartphone smartphone detection activity
智能手机智能手机检测
and help add context to glance
并帮助添加上下文 一目了然
estimation that which we'll talk about
估算的是， 我们将谈论
so some of the more traditional methods
所以一些比较传统的 方法
were sequential is detecting first the
顺序是首先检测到
head and then stepping detecting the
然后踩踏检测
shoulders the elbows the hands the
肩膀肘部 的手
depot's holistic view which has been the
仓库的整体观点 一直是
very powerful successful way for multi
非常强大的 成功方式
person pose estimation is performing a
人物姿势估计正在执行
regression of detecting body parts from
检测身体部位的回归
the entire image it's not sequentially
整个图像不是顺序的
stitching bodies together it's detecting
将身体缝合在一起它的检测
the left elbow the right elbow the hands
左手肘右手肘手
individually it's performing that
个别它正在表演
detection and then stitching everything
检测然后缝合一切
together afterwards allowing you to deal
之后一起让你交易
with the crazy deformations of the body
随着 身体 的疯狂变形
that happened the occlusions and so on
那发生了遮挡 等等
because you don't need all the joints to
因为你 不需要所有关节
be visible and with this cascade of pose
是可见的和这个级联的姿势
regressors meaning these are
回归量意味着这些
convolutional neural networks had taken
卷积神经网络已经采取
a raw image and produce an XY position
原始图像并生成 XY位置
of their estimate of each individual
他们对每个人的估计
joint input as an image output is an
联合输入作为图像输出是
estimate of a joint of elbow shoulder
估计 肘关节 的关节
whatever one of several landmarks and
几个标志性建筑中的任何一个
then you can build on top of that every
那么你就可以建立在每一个顶部
estimation zooms in on that particular
估计放大了那个 特定的
area and performs a finer and finer
区域，并执行更精细
grain estimation of the exact position
谷物估计的确切 位置
of the Joye repeating it over and over
Joye一遍又一 遍地 重复着它
and over so through this process we can
通过这个过程，我们可以
do part detection and multi-person and
部分检测和多人和
multi-person scene that contain multiple
包含 多 个人的多人 场景
people so we can detect the the head the
人们所以我们可以检测出头部了
neck here the hands the elbows shown in
脖子在这里肘部所示的手
the various images on the right that
右边的各种图像是
don't have an understanding who the head
不了解谁的头
the elbows the the hands belong to
手所属的肘部
it's just performing a detection without
它只是在没有执行检测
trying to do individual person detection
试图做个人检测
first and then finally connecting or not
首先，然后最终连接或不连接
finally but next step is connecting with
最后但下一步 是与之相连
part affinity fields is connecting those
部分亲和力字段正在连接它们
parts together so first you detect
部分在一起， 所以首先你发现
individual parts then you connect them
各个部分，然后你连接 它们
together and then through bipartite
一起，然后通过双方
matching you determine which is who is
匹配你确定谁是谁
that each individual body part most
每个人身体最重要的部分
likely belonging to so you kind of
可能属于你所以
stitch the different people together in
把不同的人缝在一起
the scene after
经过 现场
the detection is performed with the CNN
用CNN进行检测
we use this approach for detecting the
我们使用这种方法来检测
upper body specifically the shoulders
上身特别是肩膀
the neck and the head eyes nose ears
颈部和 头部的 眼睛是鼻子的耳朵
that is used to determine the the
那是用来确定 的
position of the driver relative to the
司机的位置相对于
standard dummy position for example
例如标准虚拟位置
looking during autopilot driving
在自动驾驶仪驾驶期间看
30-minute periods we can look at on the
30分钟的时间 我们可以看看
x-axis is time and the y-axis is the
x轴是时间 ， y轴 是
position of the neck point that I
我的颈部位置
pointed out in the previous slide that
在上一张幻灯片中指出了这一点
the the the midpoint between the two
两者之间的 的 中点
shoulders the neck is the position over
肩膀的 脖子是 位置
time relative to where it began this is
相 对于它 开始的 时间 而言
the slouching the sinking into the seat
懒散地沉入座位
allowing the car to know that
让汽车知道这一点
information and allowing us or the
信息并 允许我们或
designers of safety systems and all that
安全系统的设计者和所有这些
information is really important we can
信息对我们 来说 非常重要
use the same body pose algorithm to from
使用相同的身体姿势算法来自
the perspective of the vehicle outside
车外的视角
the vehicle perspective so the vehicle
车辆视角如此车辆
looking out is doing the as opposed to
望着正在反对
just plain pedestrian detection using
只是简单的行人检测 使用
body pose estimation again here in
身体姿势估计再次在这里
Kendall Square vehicles crossing
肯德尔广场车辆穿越
observing pedestrians making crossing
观察行人过马路
decisions and performing body pose
决定和表演身体姿势
estimation which allows you to then
估计哪个允许你呢
generate visualizations like this and
生成像这样的可视化
gain understanding like this on the
在这上获得这样的理解
x-axis is time on the y-axis is on the
x轴是y轴上 的时间
top plot in blue is the speed of the
在蓝顶情节 的 速度
vehicle the speed of the vehicle the ego
车辆的速度是自我
vehicle from which the camera is
相机所在的车辆
observing the scene and on the bottom in
观察现场和底部
green up and down as a binary value
绿色上下 作为二进制 值
whether the Podesta when the pedestrian
是否Podesta当行人
is not looking at the car one when the
是不是在看车的时候
pedestrian is looking at the car so we
行人正在看车，所以我们
can look at thousands of episodes like
可以看看成千上万的剧集
this crossing decisions nonverbal
这种交叉决定是非语言的
communication decisions and determine
沟通决定和决定
using body pose estimation the dynamics
使用身体姿势估计动力学
of this nonverbal
这种非语言的
here just nearby by media lab crossing
这附近就是媒体实验室 穿越
there's a pedestrian approaches we can
我们可以采用行人路
look in green there when the pedestrian
当行人看时， 绿色那里
glasses looks away glasses the car looks
眼镜看起来像汽车看起来的眼镜
away fascinating glance behavior that
远迷人的一瞥行为
happens interesting most people look
大多数人看起来很有趣
away before they cross same thing here
在他们穿过同样的东西之前离开
this is just an example we have
这只是我们的一个例子
thousands of these body pose estimation
成千上万的身体姿势估计
allows you to get this fine-grained
允许你获得这种细粒度
information about the pedestrian glance
有关行人一瞥的信息
behavior pedestrian body behavior
行为人体行为
hesitation glass classification one of
犹豫玻璃分类之一
the most important things in driving is
驾驶中最重要的事情是
determining where drivers are looking it
确定司机在哪里看
if there's any sensing that I advocate
如果有任何感觉， 我提倡
and is has the most impact in the
并且在影响最大
driving context is for the car to know
驾驶环境是让汽车知道的
where the driver is looking and at the
司机正在寻找的地方
very crude region level information of
非常原始的区域级信息
is the driver looking on road or off
被司机看路面上或关闭
road that's what we mean by glance
道路，这就是我们所说的一瞥
classification it's not the standard
分类它不是标准
gaze estimation problem of X Y Z
XYZ的注视估计问题
determining where the eye pose and the
确定 眼睛的姿势和姿势
head pose combined to determine where
头部姿势结合起来确定 在哪里
the driver is looking no this is
司机看起来 不是这个
classifying two regions on road off-road
在越野公路上划分两个区域
or six regions on road off road left
或离开道路的六个地区
right center stack rearview mirror and
右中心堆栈后视镜和
instrument cluster so it's region based
仪表盘所以它是基于区域的
glance allocation not the geometric gaze
扫视分配不是几何凝视
estimation problem why is that important
估计问题为什么那么重要
it allows you to address it as a machine
它允许您将 其作为一台机器 来 处理
learning problem it's a subtle but
学习问题这是一个微妙的但是
critical point every problem we try to
关键点我们尝试的每一个问题
solve in human sensing in driver sensing
在驾驶员感知中解决人体感知问题
has to be learn about from data
必须从数据中 学习
otherwise it's not it's not amenable to
否则它不适合
application in the real world we can't
在现实世界中我们不能应用
design systems in the lab that are
设计系统是实验室
deployed without learning if they
部署而不学习 他们
involve a human it's possible to do slam
涉及人类可以做大满贯
localization by having really good
通过 非常好的 本地化
sensors and doing localization using
传感器和使用的本地化
those sensors without much learning it's
那些没有太多学习的传感器
not possible to design systems that deal
不可能设计 出处理的系统
with lighting variability and the full
用灯光变化和全
variability of human behavior without
没有 人的行为的可变性
being able to learn so gaze estimation
能够学习如此凝视估计
the geometric approach of finding the
寻找的几何方法
landmarks in the face and from those
面部和 那些地标
landmarks determining the the Jeremie
确定Jeremie的地标
the orientation of the head and the
头部和头部的方向
orientation of the eyes there's no
眼睛的方向没有
learning there outside of actually
实际上在那里学习
training the systems to detect the
训练系统 检测
different landmarks if we convert this
如果我们转换 这个不同的地标
into a gaze classification problem shown
进入所示的凝视分类问题
here glass classification is when taking
这里玻璃分类是在服用时
the raw video stream determining in post
在帖子中确定的原始视频流
so humans are annotating this video is
所以人类正在诠释这个视频
the driver which region the driver is
司机是哪个区域的司机
looking at that's we're able to do by
看着我们能够做到的
converting the problem into a simple
将问题转化为简单的问题
variant of classification on-road
公路分类的变种
off-road left-right the same can be done
越野左右同样可以做到
for pedestrians left forward right it
对于行人左前方吧
can annotate regions of where they are
可以注释它们所在的区域
looking and using that kind of
寻找和使用那种
classification approach determine are
分类方法确定
they looking at the cars or not are they
他们看着汽车与否
looking away are they looking at their
他们看着他们正在看着他们
smartphone without doing the 3d gaze
智能手机没有做3d凝视
estimation again it's a subtle point but
再次估计它是一个微妙的点， 但是
think about it if you wanted to estimate
如果 你想 估计，请考虑一下
exactly where they're looking
他们正在寻找的确切位置
you need that ground truth you don't
你需要那些你没有的基本事实
have that ground truth unless you there
除非你在那里，否则有这个基本事实
there's no in the real world data
在现实世界中没有数据
there's no way to get the information
没有办法获取信息
about where exactly people were looking
关于 人们在 哪里 看
you're only inferring so you have to
你只是 推断，所以你必须
convert it into a region based
将其转换为基于区域
classification problem in order to be
分类问题是为了
able to train your networks on this and
能够训练 你的网络 和
the pipeline is the same the source
管道是 相同 的源
video here the face the the 30 frames a
视频在这里面对30帧a
second video coming in of the drivers
第二个视频进入了 司机
face of the human face there is some
面对人脸有一些
degree of calibration that's required
需要的校准程度
you have to determine approximately
你必须大致确定
where the sensor is that's taking in the
传感器正在 接收的地方
image especially for the glance
图像特别 是一目了然
classification task because its region
分类任务因为它的 区域
based
基于
needs to be able to estimate where the
需要能够估计其中
forward roadway is where the the camera
前进道路是摄像机的所在
frame is relative the world frame the
框架是相对世界框架的
video stabilization and the face front
视频稳定和 面对面
elevation all the basic processing
提升所有基本处理
they've removed the vibration of the
他们已经删除 的振动
noise that remove the physical movement
噪声 除去的 物理移动
of the head that removed the shaking of
头部 的 时候删掉的晃动
the car in order to be able to determine
汽车以便 能够确定
stuff about eye movement and blink
眼睛运动 和眨眼的东西
dynamics and finally with the neural
动力学，最后与神经
networks there is nothing left except
网络没有什么可以留下的
taking in the raw video of the face for
接受面部的原始视频
the glass classification tasks and the
玻璃分类任务和
eye for the cognitive load tasks raw
关注认知负荷任务原始
pixels that's the input to these
像素是这些的输入
networks and the output is whatever the
网络和输出是什么
training data is and we'll mention each
培训数据是，我们将提到每个
one so whether that's cognitive load
那么这是否是认知负荷
glance emotion drowsiness the input is
一瞥 情感困倦的输入是
the raw pixels and the output is
原始像素 和 输出是
whatever you have data for data is
无论你有什么数据数据是
everything here the face an alignment
这里的一切都是面对面的
problem which is a traditional geometric
问题是传统的 几何问题
approach to this problem is designing
解决这个问题的方法是设计
algorithms that are able to detect
能够 检测的 算法
accurately the individual landmarks in
准确地说明了各个地标
the face and from that estimate the
面子和那个估计 的
geometry of the head pose for the class
班级头部姿势的几何形状
of
的
in version we perform the same kind of
在版本中 我们执行相同的类型
alignment or with the same kind of face
对齐或与同一种脸型
detection in alignment to determine
检测对齐以确定
where the head is but once we have that
头部在哪里， 但一旦我们拥有它
we pass in just the raw pixels and
我们只传入原始 像素 和
perform the classification on that as
对其进行分类
opposed to doing the estimation its
反对这样做估计 其
classification allowing you to perform
分类允许你 执行
what's shown there on the bottom is the
什么是显示有在 底部是
real-time classification of where the
实时 分类在哪里
driver is looking Road left right center
司机正在寻找道路左右中心
stack instrument cluster and rearview
堆栈仪表组和后视图
mirror and as I mentioned annotation
镜像和我提到的注释
tooling is key so we have a total 5
工具是关键所以我们共有 5个
billion video frames one and a half
十亿个视频帧一个半
billion of the face that would take tens
数十亿的面孔需要数十
of millions of dollars to annotate just
只需数百万美元即可注释
for the glass classification fully so we
对于玻璃分类完全如此我们
have to figure out what to annotate in
必须弄清楚要注释的内容
order to trade and you'll networks to
交易，你会网络
perform this task and what we annotate
执行此任务以及我们注释的内容
is the things that the network is not
是 网络不是 的东西
confident about the moments of
对... 的时刻充满信心
highlighting variation the partial
突出部分变化
occlusions from the light or self
来自光明或自我的遮挡
occlusion and the moving out of frame
遮挡和移出框架
the outer frame occlusions all the
所有的外框遮挡
difficult cases going from frame to
困难的案例从框架到
frame to frame here and the different
框架到这里框架和 不同
pipeline starting at the table going at
管道起点在餐桌上要 在
the bottom whenever the classification
每当分类底部
has a low confidence we pass it to the
信心不足 我们把它传递给了
human it's simple we rely on the human
人类很简单， 我们依靠人类
only when the classifier is not
只有当分类器不是时
confident and the fundamental trade-off
自信和基本的权衡
in all of these systems is what is the
在所有这些系统中是什么
accuracy we're willing to put up with
我们愿意 忍受的准确性
here in red and blue and red is human
这里红色 和蓝色 ，红色是人类
choice decision and blue as a machine
选择决定和蓝色 作为一台机器
tasks in red we select the video we want
红色的任务我们选择 我们想要 的视频
to classify in blue the the the neural
将神经分类为蓝色
network performs the face detection task
网络执行面部检测任务
localizing the camera choosing what is
选择什么是本地化相机
the angle of the camera
相机 的角度
and provides a trade opportunity and
并提供贸易机会和
percent frames it can annotate so
它可以注释的百分比帧数
certainly and you'll networking at a
当然，你会 在一个网络
glance for the entire data set they
浏览整个数据集
would achieve accuracy in the case of
在这种情况下会达到准确性
glass classification of nine low 90%
玻璃分类九低 90％
classification on the sixth glass task
关于 第六次玻璃任务的分类
now if you want a higher accuracy that
现在，如果你想要更高的精确度
it will only be able to achieve that for
它只能 实现这一目标
us for a smaller fraction of frames
我们用于 较小部分的帧
that's the choice
这是选择
and then a human has to go in and
然后一个人必须进去
perform the annotation of the frames
执行 框架 的注释
that the algorithm was not confident
算法没有信心
about and it repeats over and over the
关于 和它一遍又一遍地重复
algorithm is then trained on the frames
然后在帧上训练算法
that were annotated by the human and
这是由人和人注释的
repeats this process over and over on
一遍又一遍 的 重复这个过程
the frames until everything is annotated
框架直到所有内容都被注释
yes yes absolutely
是的，绝对是的
the question was do you ever observe
问题是你有没有观察过
that the classifier is highly confident
分类器非常自信
about the incorrect class yep right
关于错误的类，是的
question was hot well then how do you
问题很热，那么你怎么样
how do you deal with that how do you
你怎么处理 你怎么样
account for that how do you account for
说明你如何解释
the fact that highly confident
高度自信的事实
predictions can be highly wrong yeah
预测可能是非常错误的
false positives false positives that
误报误报是
you're really confident in there there's
你真的对那里有信心
no at least in our experience there's no
至少根据 我们的经验，没有
good answer for that except more more
对此 更好的答案 除了更多
and more training data on the things
以及有关事物的更多培训数据
you're not confident about that usually
你通常对此没有信心
seems to deal generalize over cases we
似乎对我们的案例进行了概括
don't encounter obvious large categories
不要遇到明显的大类
of data where you're really confident
对你真正有信心的数据
about the wrong thing usually some
关于错误的事情通常是一些
degree of human annotation fixes most
人类注释程度最大
problems
问题
annotating the low the low confidence
贬低低信心
part of the data
部分数据
solves all incorrect issues but of
解决所有不正确的问题但是
course that's not always true in the
当然，这并不总是正确 的
general case that you can imagine a lot
一般情况下 你可以想象 很多
of scenarios whether that's not true for
情况是否不 适用
example one one one thing they always
例如，他们总是一件事
perform is for each individual person we
表演是针对我们每个人
usually entertain a large amount of the
通常会招待大量的
data manually no matter what so we have
手动数据，无论我们有什么
to make sure that the neural network has
确保神经网络具有
seen that person in the various and the
看到那个人 在各种各样的
various ways their face looks like with
各种方式自己的脸看起来 像
glasses with different hair with
不同头发的眼镜
different a lighting variation so we
不同的照明变化所以我们
want to manually annotate that it's
想要手动注释它
overtime we're allowing the machine to
超时我们允许机器
do more and more of the work
做越来越多 的工作
so what's resulting in this in the
是什么导致了这一点
glance classification cases you can do
你可以做一瞥分类案例
real-time classification you can give
你可以给出的实时分类
the car information about whether the
关于是否的汽车信息
driver is looking on road or off road
司机正在寻找 道路或越野
this is critical information for the car
这是 汽车的关键信息
to understand and you want to pause for
理解，你想暂停
a second to realize that when you're
一秒钟才意识到 你什么时候
driving a car for those our driver for
为 我们的司机驾驶汽车
those that driven any kind of car with
那些驾驶任何一种车的人
any kind of automation it has no idea
任何类型的自动化它都不知道
about what you're up to at all there's
关于你所做的 一切
no it doesn't have any information about
不，它没有任何 关于的 信息
the driver except if they're touching
司机， 除非他们正在接触
the steering wheel or not more and more
方向盘与否也越来越 多
now with the GM supercruise vehicle and
现在与通用汽车超级车辆和
Tesla now has added a dryer facing
特斯拉现在增加了一个烘干机面
camera that slowly started to think
慢慢开始 思考的相机
about moving towards perceiving the
关于走向 感知
driver but most vehicles on the road
司机， 但大多数车辆在路上
today have no knowledge of the driver
今天不了解司机
this knowledge is almost common sense
这种知识几乎是常识
and trivial for the car to have the it's
并且让汽车拥有它的微不足道
common sense how important this
常识这有多重要
information is where the driver is
信息是司机所在的位置
looking that's the glance classification
看那是一瞥分类
problem and again emphasizing that we've
问题再次强调我们已经
converted it's been three decades of
转换它已经三十年了
work on gaze estimation yet gaze
致力于凝视估计而凝视
estimation is doing head pose estimation
估计是做头部姿势估计
so the geometric orientation of the head
所以头部的几何方向
combining the orientation of the eyes
结合 眼睛 的方向
and using that combined information to
并使用该组合信息
determine where the person is looking
确定此 人的目的地
will convert that into a classification
将其转换为分类
problem so the standard gaze estimation
问题所以标准凝视估计
definition is not a machine learning
定义不是机器学习
problem
问题
classification is a machine learning
分类是机器学习
problem this transformation is key
问题 这种 转变是关键
emotion human emotion is a fascinating
情感人类的情感是一种迷人的
thing so the same kind of pipeline
东西所以同样 的管道
stabilization cleaning of the data raw
稳定清理数据原始
pixels in and then the classification is
以像素为单位，然后将分类是
emotion the problem with emotion if I
如果我，情绪问题
may speak as an expert human not am NOT
可以作为专家说话而不是
an expert in emotion is just an expert
情感专家就是专家
of being human is that there is a lot of
作为人类的是有很多
ways that's a sodomize emotion to
这种方式是 一种鸡奸情绪
categorize emotion to define emotion
将情绪分类以定义情绪
whether that's for the the primary
是否是主要的
emotion of the para scale would love joy
para scale的情感 会喜欢快乐
surprise anger sadness fear there's a
惊讶的愤怒悲伤恐惧有一个
lot of ways to mix those together to
很多方法可以将它们混合在一起
break those apart into hierarchical
打破这些分裂成 层次
taxonomies and the way we think about it
分类法以及我们 对它的思考 方式
in the driving context at least there is
在 驱动情况下至少 有
a general emotion recognition task sort
一般的情感识别任务 排序
of I mentioned I'll mention it but it's
我提到过我会提到它，但它是
kind of how we think about primary
我们如何看待初级
emotions is detecting the the broad
情绪正在发现
categories of emotion of joy and anger
喜悦和愤怒的情感类别
of disgust and surprise and then there
令人厌恶和惊讶然后在那里
is application specific emotion
是特定于应用的情感
recognition where you're using the
识别你正在使用的地方
facial expressions that all the various
所有各种各样的面部表情
ways that we can deform our face to
我们可以改变面子的方式
communicate information to determine the
通信信息 来确定
specific question about the interaction
关于互动的 具体问题
of the driver so I'll first for the
司机所以我先是为了
general case these are the building
一般情况下 这些是建筑物
blocks I mean there's there's countless
块我的意思是那里有 无数的
ways of deforming the face that we use
使我们使用 的脸部变形的方法
to communicate with each other there's
互相 有交流
42 individual facial muscles that can be
可以是 42个单独的面部肌肉
used to form those expressions one of
用来形成那些表达式之一
our favorite
我们的最爱
work with is the effective SDK this is
与工作是有效的SDK，这是
their their their task with the general
他们与将军的任务
emotion recognition task is taking in
情绪识别任务 正在进行中
raw pixels and determining categories of
原始像素和确定的类别
emotion very subtleties of that emotion
情绪非常微妙的那种情绪
in the general case producing a
在一般情况下生产一个
classification of anger disgust fear
愤怒的分类厌恶恐惧
surprise so on and then mapping I mean
如此惊喜然后映射我的意思
essentially what these algorithms are
基本上这些算法是什么
doing whether whether they using deep
做是否 他们 使用深
neural networks or not whether using
是否使用神经网络
face alignment to do the landmark
面对齐做地标
detection and then tracking those
检测然后跟踪那些
landmarks over time to do the facial
随着时间的推移做地标的地标
actions they're determined they're
他们确定的行动是他们的
mapping the expressions the component
映射组件的表达式
their various expressions who can make
他们 可以做出 的各种表达 方式
with their eyebrows or their nose and
用他们的眉毛或他们的鼻子和
mouth and eyes to map them to the
嘴 和眼睛将它们映射到
emotion so I'd like to highlight one
情绪，所以我想强调 一个
because I think it's an illustrative one
因为我认为这是 一个 说明性的
for joy an expression of joy is smiling
快乐的表达 正在微笑
so there's an increased likelihood that
所以可能性增加了
you observe a smiling expression on the
你观察到一个微笑的表情
face when joy is experienced or vice
当喜悦 经历或恶习时面对
versa if there's an increased
反之亦然， 如果有增加
probability of a smile there's an
微笑的可能性有一个
increased probability of emotion of joy
增加快乐情绪的可能性
being experienced and then joy an
经历，然后快乐
experience has a decreased probability
经验的可能性降低
likelihood of brow raising and brow
眉毛抬起和眉毛的可能性
following so if you see a smile that's a
如果你看到微笑就是这样的话
that's a plus for joy if you see brow
如果你看到眉毛 ，这是一个加号
raised bright for Oh
哦 募集 亮
brow furrow is a minus for joy that's
额头皱纹是欢乐减去这
for the general emotional recognition
对于一般的情感认可
task that's been well studied that's
这个任务得到了很好的 研究
sort of the core of affective computing
一种情感 计算的核心
movement from from the visual
来自视觉的运动
perspective again from the computer
从计算机再次透视
vision perspective from the application
从应用程序的 愿景角度
of specific perspective which were
具体的观点是什么
really focused on again data is
真正专注于数据的是
everything what what are you annotating
什么是你注释的一切
we can take here we have a large-scale
我们可以在这里采取大规模的
data set of drivers interacting with a
与a交互的驱动程序数据集
voice based navigation system so they're
基于语音的导航系统，所以他们
tasked with in various vehicles to enter
在各种车辆 进入任务
a navigation so with they're talking to
导航，所以他们正在交谈
their GPS using their voice this is for
他们的GPS使用他们的声音这是为了
depending on the vehicle depending on
根据车辆 取决于
the system in most cases an incredibly
在大多数情况下 ， 该系统 令人难以置信
frustrating experience so we have them
令人沮丧的经历让我们拥有它们
perform this task and then
执行此任务然后
the annotation is self-report after the
注释是自我报告后 的
task they say on a scale of 1 to 10 how
他们说的任务规模是 1到10怎么样
frustrating was this experience and when
令人沮丧的是这种体验和时间
you see on top is is the expressions
你看到的是表达式
detected and associated with a satisfied
检测到并 与满意 相关联
a person who said a a 10 on the
一个人谁说AA 10 对
satisfaction so a 1 in the frustration
在无奈满意这样一个 1
scale was perfectly satisfied with a
规模完全满足于
voice based interaction on the bottom is
底部 基于语音的交互 是
frustrated as a believin 9 on the
作为失意的一个believin 9
frustration scale so the feature the
无奈规模因此该功能的
strongest there the expression remember
那里表达最强的记忆
joy smile was the strongest indicator of
欢乐的笑容是最强烈的指标
frustration for all our subjects that
我们所有科目都感到沮丧
was the strongest expression smile was
微笑是最强烈的表达
the thing that was always there for
这是一直存在 的 东西
frustration there's other various
沮丧还有其他各种各样的
frowning that followed and shaking the
皱着眉头随后摇晃着
head and so on but smiles were there so
头等等，但微笑就在那里
that shows you the kind of clean
显示你的那种干净
difference between general emotion
一般情绪之间的差异
recognition tasks and the
识别任务和
application-specific
专用
here perhaps they enjoyed an absurd
也许他们喜欢荒唐
moment of joy at the frustration that
欢乐的时刻在无奈地 说 ，
were experiencing you can sort of get
正在体验你可以获得
philosophical about it but the practical
哲学，但实用
nature is they were frustrated with the
自然是他们与沮丧
experience and we're using the 42 most
经验，我们使用最多的42
of the face to make expressions to do
面部表情要做
classification of frustrated or not and
分类沮丧或不 和
their data does the work not the
他们的数据不是工作而是工作
algorithms it's the annotation a quick
算法它是一个快速的注释
mention for the AGI class next week for
提到下周 的AGI课程
the artificial general intelligence
人工智能
class one of the competition's we're
一类比赛的我们 的
doing is we have a JavaScript face
做的是我们有一个 JavaScript 面孔
that's trained with a neural network to
这与神经网络来训练的
form various expressions to communicate
形成各种表达来沟通
with the observer so we're interested in
与观察者一起， 所以我们感兴趣
creating emotion which is a nice mirror
创造情感，这是一面很好的镜子
coupling of the emotional recognition
情感认知的耦合
problem it's gonna be super cool
这个问题会非常 酷
cognitive load we're starting to get to
我们开始认识到的认知负荷
the eyes
眼睛
cognitive load is the degree to which a
认知负荷是一种程度
human being is accessing their memory or
人类正在访问他们的记忆或
as Lawson thought how hard they're
劳森认为他们有多难
working in their mind to recollect
在他们的脑海 里回想起来
something to think about something as
值得思考 的 东西
cognitive load and to do a quick pause
认知负荷并快速暂停
of eyes as the window to cognitive load
眼睛作为认知负荷的窗口
eyes the window to the mind there's a
眼睛窗口心中 有一个
different ways the eyes move so there's
眼睛移动的方式不同，所以有
pupils the black part of the eye they
瞳孔是他们眼睛的黑色部分
can expand and and contract based on
可以扩大和合同，并根据
various factors including the lighting
各种因素， 包括 照明
variations in the scene but they also
场景的变化， 但他们 也
expand and contract based on cognitive
基于认知扩展和收缩
load that's a that's a strong signal
加载这是一个强烈的信号
they can also move around
他们也可以四处走动
there's ballistic movement saccades when
有弹道运动的时候会出现跳伞运动
we look around eyes jump around the
环顾周围的眼皮跳
scene they can also do something called
场景他们也可以做一些 叫做的 事
smooth pursuit when you and connecting
当你和连接时顺利追求
to our animal past you can see a
我们的动物 过去你可以看到一个
delicious meal
美味的一餐
flying by or running by that your eyes
通过你的眼睛飞行或奔跑
can follow it perfectly they're not
可以完全遵循它们，但它们不是
jumping around so when we read a book
当我们读一本书时 跳来跳去
our eyes are using saccadic movements
我们的眼睛正在使用扫视运动
where they jump around and when the
他们在哪里跳来跳去的时候
purse muth pursuit the eye is moving
钱包muth追求眼睛在移动
perfectly smoothly those are the kinds
非常顺利的是那些种类
of movements who have to work with and
必须与之合作的运动
cognitive load can be detected by
认知负荷可以通过检测
looking at various factors of the eye
看着 眼睛的各种因素
the blink dynamics the eye movement and
眨眼动态的眼球运动和
the eye the pupil diameter the problem
眼睛瞳孔直径问题
is in the real world and real world data
是在现实世界和现实世界的数据
with lighting variations everything goes
随着照明变化一切顺利
out the window in terms of using pupil
在使用瞳孔方面窗外
diameter which is the standard way to
直径这是 标准的方式 来
measure non-contact way to measure
衡量非接触式测量方法
cognitive load in the lab when you can
在实验室认知负荷时，你可以
control lighting conditions and use
控制照明条件和使用
infrared cameras when you can't all that
红外摄像机，你不能那么多
goes out the window and all you have is
走出窗外，你拥有的只是
the blink dynamics and the eye movement
眨眼动态和眼球运动
so neural networks to the rescue
所以神经网络来救援
3d convolutional neural networks in this
在这个 3D卷积神经网络
case we take a sequences of images that
情况下，我们采取的图像的序列， 即
I through time and use 3d convolutions
我通过时间和使用3D卷积
as opposed to 2d convolutions on the
而不是2d卷积
left is everything we've talked about
左边是我们无话不谈
previous to this as 2d convolutions when
在此之前作为2d卷积时
the convolution filter is operating on
卷积滤波器正在运行
the
该
XY 2d image every channel is operated on
操作 每个通道的 XY 2d图像
by the filter individual separately 3d
由过滤器个体分别为3d
convolutions combine those convolve
卷积结合了那些卷积
across the across multiple images across
跨越多个图像
multiple channels therefore being able
因此多个渠道能够
to learn the dynamics of the scene
学习 场景 的动态
through time as well not just spatially
通过时间不仅仅是在空间上
temporal and data data is everything for
时间和数据数据就是一切
a cognitive load we have in this case 92
我们 在这种情况下的认知负担92
drivers so how do we sort of perform the
司机所以我们如何执行
cognitive load classification task we
认知负荷分类任务我们
have these drivers driving on the
让这些司机 开车
highway and performing the what's called
公路和执行 什么 叫做
the n-back task zero back one back to
n-back任务将一个回零
back and that task involves hearing
回来，那个任务涉及听证会
numbers being read to you and then
数字正在读给你然后
recalling those numbers one at a time so
在一次回想起这些数字之一 ，所以
one zero back the system gives you a
一个零回系统 给你 一个
number seven and then you have to just
七号，然后你必须
say that number back seven and it keeps
说这个数字 回七，它保持
repeating that's easy it's supposed to
重复这很容易它应该
be the easy task one back is when you
当 你 回来时， 这 是一件容易的事
hear number you have to remember it and
听到号码你必须 记住它
then that for the next number you have
那么你有下一个号码
to say the number previous to that so
说出之前的数字
you kind of have to keep one number in
你必须 保留一个号码
your memory always and not get
你的记忆永远不会得到
distracted by the new information coming
被 新 信息分散注意力
up but to back you have to do that two
起来但要回来你必须做那 两个
numbers back so you have to use memory
数字回来所以你必须使用记忆
more and more went to back so cognitive
越来越多的 人回归认知
load is higher and higher okay so what
什么是负载越高越好
do we do we use face alignment face
我们是否使用面部对齐面
front elevation and detecting the eye
正面抬高并检测眼睛
closest to the camera and extract the
最接近相机并提取
eye region and now we have this nice raw
眼睛区域，现在我们有这个很好的原料
pixels of the eye region across six
六个眼睛区域的像素
seconds of video and we take that and
几秒钟的视频，我们采取了 这个和
put that in as a 3d convolutional neural
把 它 作为一个三维卷积神经
network and classify simply one of three
网络和分类只是三个中的一个
classes zero back one back and two back
班级归零一回， 两回
so we have a ton of data of people on
所以我们有 很多人 的数据
the highway performing these tasks and
高速公路执行这些任务和
back tasks and that forms the
后面的任务，形成了
classification supervised learning
分类监督学习
training data that's it the input is 90
训练数据 输入是90
images it's at 15 frames a second
它的图像是每秒15帧
and the output is one of three classes
输出是三个类之一
face fronto ization i should mention is
我应该提到的是面对额头化
the technique developed under for face
为面子开发的技术
recognition because most face
因为大多数人都认可
recognition tasks require frontal face
识别任务需要正面
orientation is also what we use here to
方向也是 我们在这里使用的方式
normalize everything that we can focus
规范我们可以关注的一切
in on the exact blink it's taking the
在确切的眨眼之间它正在接受
it's taking whatever the orientation of
它正在采取 任何方向
the face and projecting into the frontal
脸部和突出到正面
position taking the raw pixels of the
采取原始像素的位置
face is detecting the eye region zooming
脸部正在检测眼睛区域变焦
in and grabbing the eye where you find
在你找到的地方抓住眼睛
and this is where the intuition builds
这就是直觉的建立
it it's a fascinating one what's being
它是一个迷人的东西
plotted here is the relative movement of
这里绘制的是相对运动
the pupil the relative movement of the
瞳孔的相对运动
eye based on a different cognitive loads
眼睛基于不同的认知负荷
for cognitive load on the left of zero
对于 零 左边的认知负荷
so when your mind is not that lost in
所以当你的思想 不是那么迷失的时候
thought and cognitive load of two on the
两个人的思想和认知负担
right when it is lost in thought the eye
当它 在思想眼中迷失的 时候
moves a lot less eye is more focused on
移动少了很多眼睛更侧重 于
the forward roadway that's an
前进的道路是一个
interesting finding but it's only in
有趣的发现， 但它只是在
aggregate and that's what the neural
聚合，这就是神经
neural network is task would do it with
神经网络是任务会做到的
extracting an a frame-by-frame basis
提取 一帧接一帧的基础
this is a standard 3d convolutional
这是一个标准的3d卷积
architecture again taking in the image
建筑再次采取图像
sequence is the input cognitive load
序列是输入的认知 负荷
classification is the output and
分类是输出和
classifying on the right is the accuracy
在右边分类是准确性
that's able to achieve of 86% that's
这是能够实现的 86％ 这
pretty cool from real-world data the
来自真实世界的数据很酷的
idea is that you can just plop in a
想法是你可以 只是一个人
webcam get the video going in going into
摄像头让视频 进入
the neural network and this predicting
神经网络和 这种 预测
it continued
它 继续
a stream from zero to two of cognitive
从零到两个 认知 的流
load because every single zero want back
因为每一个零想要回来加载
one back to back classes are have a
一个背靠背的课程 有一个
confidence that's associated with them
与他们相关的信心
so you can turn that into a real value
所以你可以把它变成真正的价值
between zero and two and when you see
在零 到 两之间，当你看到
here's a plot of three of the people on
这是 三个人的情节
the team here driving a car performing a
这里的车队开着车表演
task of conversation and in white
谈话和白色的任务
showing the cognitive load frame by
通过显示认知负荷 框架
frame a thirty frames a second
帧一个三十个帧 的第二
estimating the cognitive load of each of
估计每个人的认知负荷
the drivers on from zero to two on the
驾驶员从0到2上
y-axis so these are high cognitive load
y轴因此这些都是高认知负荷
and showing in on the bottom red and
并显示在底部的红色和
yellow of high medium cognitive load and
黄色的高中等认知负荷和
when everybody's silent the cognitive
当每个人都沉默 认知时
load goes down so we can perform now
负载下降所以我们现在可以执行
with this simple neural network with the
用这个简单的神经网络
training data that we formed we can
训练我们形成的数据我们 可以
extend that to any arbitrary new data
将其扩展到 任意 新数据
set and generalize okay those are some
设置和概括确定那些是一些
examples of Chania neural networks can
哈尼亚神经网络的例子可以
be applied and why is this important
应用，为什么这很重要
again is while we focus on the sort of
再一次，我们专注于那种
the perception tasks of using neural
使用神经网络 的感知 任务
networks of using sensors and signal
使用传感器和信号的网络
processing to determine where we are in
处理以确定我们所处的位置
the world where the different obstacles
世界上不同的障碍
are informed trajectories around those
是围绕 这些的 通知轨迹
obstacles we are still far away from
阻碍 我们仍然远离
completely solving that problem I would
我会完全解决这个问题
argue 20 plus years away the human will
争论20多年 的人类 意志
have to be involved and so when it's the
必须参与，所以当它是
system is not able to control when the
系统无法控制何时
system is not able to perceive when
系统无法 察觉何时
there's some flawed aspect about the
有一些缺陷方面有关
perception or the driving policy the
感知或驾驶政策
human has to be involved and that's
人类必须参与其中
where we have to know let the car know
在那里我们必须知道 让汽车知道
what the human is doing that's the
什么人在做这就是
essential element of human robot
人体机器人的基本要素
interaction the most popular car in the
互动中最流行的汽车
United States today is the Ford f-150 no
美国今天是福特f-150没有
automation the thing that sort of
自动化那种东西
inspires us and makes us think that
激励我们， 让我们 思考
transportation can be fundamentally
运输可以从根本上
transformed is the Google self-driving
转型是谷歌自驾车
mo
莫
our and although our guest speakers and
我们的，虽然我们的演讲嘉宾 和
all the folks work in the autonomous
所有人都在自治中工作
vehicles but if you look at it the only
车辆，但如果你看看它的 唯一
people who are at a mass scale or
大规模的人 或
beginning to are actually injecting
开始实际注射
automation into our daily lives is the
自动化进入我们的日常生活 是
ones in between
介于两者之间
it's the Tesla's the l2 systems it's the
这是特斯拉的l2系统
tesla system the supercruise the audio
特斯拉系统 超级音响
as 90s the the vehicles that are slowly
像90年代 那样 缓慢 的车辆
adding to some degree of automation and
增加一定程度的自动化和
teaching human beings how to interact
教人类如何互动
with that automation and here's again
随着自动化，这里又来了
the the the path towards mass scale
通向大规模的道路
automation we're steering wheels removed
自动化我们 的方向盘 去除
the consideration that humans removed I
考虑到人类移除了我
believe is more than two decades away on
相信是二十多年了
the path to that we have to understand
我们必须了解的道路
and create successful human robot
并创造成功的 人类机器人
interaction approach autonomous vehicles
互动方式自动驾驶汽车
autonomous systems in a human centered
以人为本的自治系统
way the mass scale integration of these
这些方式的大规模整合
systems of the human center systems like
像 人类 中心系统的系统
to test the vehicles a Tesla is just a
测试特斯拉的车辆只是一个
small company right now the the kind of
小公司现在 的那种
l2 technologies have not truly
l2技术还没有真正实现
penetrated the the market have not
渗透市场还没有
penetrated that our vehicles even the
我们的车辆 甚至 穿透 了
Brittain the new vehicles being released
Brittain新车被释放
today I believe that happens in the
今天我相信这发生在
early 2020s and that's going to form the
20世纪20年代初 ，这将 形成
core of our algorithms that will
将成为我们算法的核心
eventually lead to the full autonomy all
最终导致所有的完全自治
of that data what I mentioned with Tesla
我在特斯拉提到的那些数据
with a 32% miles being driven all of
全部驾驶 32％的 里程
that is training data for the algorithms
这是训练 算法的 数据
the edge cases arise there that's where
边缘的情况下出现的还有这就是
we get all this data in our data set at
我们在数据集中获取所有这些数据
MIT is 400,000 miles Tesla has a billion
麻省理工学院是400,000英里特斯拉有十亿
miles so that that's all training data
英里所以这 是所有训练数据
on the way on the stairway to mass scale
在 通往大规模 楼梯的路上
automation why is this
自动化为什么会这样
important beautiful and fundamental to
重要的美丽，从根本 上
the role of AI in society I believe that
人工智能在社会中的作用我相信
self-driving cars when they're in this
当他们在这里时，自动驾驶汽车
way are focused on a human robot
方式专注于人类机器人
interaction our personal robots they're
与我们的个人机器人互动
not perception control systems tools
不是感知控制系统工具
like a Roomba performing a particular
就像Roomba表演一个 特别的
task when human life is a steak when
当人类生活是牛排时的任务
there's a fundamental transfer between
两者之间有根本的转移
of life of a human being giving their
一个人的 生命给他们的
life over to an AI system directly one
直接生活到AI系统 之一
on one is a transfer that is kind of a
在一个是转移，是一种
relationship that is one indicative of a
关系是一个指示a的关系
personal robot this is it requires all
个人机器人这是它需要的一切
the things of understanding
理解的东西
communication of trust these are
这些信任的沟通
fascinating to understand how a human
了解一个 人是 多么迷人
and robot can form trust enough to
和机器人可以形成足够的信任
create a really an almost
创造一个真正的差不多
one-to-one understanding of each other's
彼此一对一的理解
mental state learn from each other oh
精神状态互相学习哦
boy
男孩
so one of my favorite movies Good Will
所以我 最喜欢的电影之一Good Will
Hunting we're in Boston Cambridge have
狩猎我们在波士顿剑桥有
two have two gonna regret this one this
两者有两个还要遗憾 这一个 本
is Robin Williams speaking about human
是罗宾威廉姆斯谈论人类
imperfections so I'd like you to take
瑕疵所以我希望你 能接受
this quote and replace every time you
这个引用并且每次都替换
mentioned girl with car people call
提到女孩与汽车人打电话
those things imperfections Robin
那些不完美的事情罗宾
Williams is talking about his wife who
威廉姆斯正在谈论 他的妻子
passed away in the movie talking about
在电影里谈论 过世了
her imperfections they call these things
她称之为瑕疵
imperfections but they're not that's the
不完美，但他们不是那样的
good stuff and then we'll get to choose
好东西然后 我们会选择
who we let into our weird little worlds
我们让谁进入我们奇怪的小世界
you're not perfect sport and let me save
你不是完美的运动，让我拯救
you the suspense this girl you met she
你是这个女孩的悬念你遇到了她
isn't perfect to you there you know what
在那里，你知道 什么是不完美的
let me just
让我吧
the video sequences that only I know
只有我知道 的视频序列
about
关于
that's what made her my wife when she
这就是 她 做 我妻子的原因
had a puts on me - she all my pet dogs
骗了我 - 她是我的宠物狗
people call these things into fashions
人们 将 这些东西 称为 时尚
suffice no need to choose we learn to
足以没有必要选择我们 学习
obviate the words in my breath explore
避免 在我的 呼吸探索中 的话
things in suspense
悬念中的事情
he has an air attack but the question is
他有空袭， 但问题是
what am i perfect for each other
我对彼此的完美之处
[Music]
[音乐]
so the approach we're taking in building
所以我们正在建设的方法
the autonomous vehicle we are here at
我们在这里的自动驾驶汽车
MIT in our group it's the human centered
麻省理工学院在我们小组中以人为本
approach the autonomous vehicles they
他们接近自动驾驶汽车
were going to release in March of 2018
将于2018年3月发布
in the streets of Boston those who would
在波士顿街头那些愿意的人
to help please do I will talk run a
请 帮忙 ， 我会说话 跑
course on deep learning for
当然深的学问
understanding the humans of Chi 2018
了解Chi 2018的人类
will be going through tutorials that go
将会进行教程
far beyond the visual the convolutional
卷积的远远超出了视觉
neural network based detection of
基于神经网络的检测
various aspects of the face and body
面部和身体的各个方面
would look at natural language
会看 自然语言
processing voice recognition and Gans
处理语音识别和 Gans
if you're going to Chi please join next
如果你要去Chi，请加入下一个
week we have an incredible course that's
一周，我们有一个令人难以置信的课程
aims to understand to begin to explore
旨在了解开始探索
the nature of intelligence natural and
智力 的本质和 自然
artificial we have Josh Tenenbaum Ray
人工我们有Josh Tenenbaum Ray
Kurzweil Lisa Barret Nate Dubinsky
Kurzweil Lisa Barret Nate Dubinsky
looking at cognitive modeling
看着认知建模
architectures Andre karpati Stephen
架构安德烈· 卡尔帕蒂 斯蒂芬
Wolfram Richard Moyes talking about
Wolfram Richard Moyes 在谈论
autonomous weapon systems and AI safety
自主武器系统和 人工智能安全
mark Robert from Boston Dynamics and the
来自波士顿动力公司的罗伯特 和
amazing incredible robots I have and
令我惊讶的令人难以置信的机器人
Ilya sutskever from open AI and myself
来自开放AI和我自己的 Ilya sutskever
so what next for folks register for this
所以接下来 的人们会 注册这个
course you have to submit by tonight a
当然你 必须在 今晚 提交 一份
deep traffic entry that achieves a speed
实现速度的深度交通入口
of 65 miles an hour and I hope you
每小时65英里，我希望你
continue to submit more that win the
继续提交更多赢得的
competition the high performer award
竞争高绩效奖
will be given to folks the very few
将会给 极少数人
folks who achieved 70 miles an hour
每小时 达到 70英里的人们
faster we will continue rolling out seg
我们将继续更快地推出seg
fuse having hit a few snags and invested
保险丝遇到了一些障碍并投入了资金
a few thousands of dollars in the
几千美元
sanitation process of annotating a
注释的卫生过程
large-scale data set for you guys we'll
我们将为您提供大规模的数据集
continue this competition that will take
继续本次比赛将采取
us into
我们进入
into a submission to his nips where we'd
在我们的地方 提交 到他的nips
hope to submit the results for this
希望 为此提交结果
competition and deep crash the deeper
竞争和深度崩溃 更深层次
enforcement learning these competitions
执法学习这些比赛
will continue through May 2018 I hope
将继续到2018年5月我希望
you stay tuned and participate
你保持关注和参与
there's upcoming classes the a GI class
即将上课的 GI课程
I encourage you to come to is going to
我鼓励 你们来 是要
be fascinating and there's so many cool
很有魅力， 而且 很酷
interesting ideas that we're going to
那我们要有趣的想法
explore it's gonna be awesome
探索它会很棒
there's an introduction to deep learning
有深度学习 的 介绍
course that I'm also part of will get a
当然，我也会参与 其中
little bit more applied and get folks
更多应用并得到人们
who are interested in the the very basic
谁对 最基本的 感兴趣
algorithms of deep learning how to get
深度学习的算法如何 获得
started with those hands-on and there's
从那些动手开始，那就是
an awesome class that ran last year for
去年参加的一个很棒的课程
those who took this class last year we
那些去年上课的人我们
also talked about it on the the global
还在全球范围内谈到了它
business of AI and robotics the slides
人工智能和 机器人技术 的幻灯片
are online I encourage you to click a
在线我鼓励你点击 一个
link on there and register it's in the
链接在那里并注册 它在
spring it's once a week and it's truly
它每周一次，它是真的
brings together a lot of
汇集了很多
cross-disciplinary folks to talk about
跨学科的人谈谈
ideas of artificial intelligence and the
人工智能 和 想法
role of AI and robotics and society it's
人工智能和机器人技术以及社会的作用
an awesome class and if you're
一个很棒的课程，如果你是
interested in applying deep learning
有兴趣应用深度学习
methods in the automotive space come
汽车领域的方法来了
work with us we have a lot of
与我们合作我们有 很多
fascinating problems to to solve or
有趣的问题 来 解决或
collaborate so with that I'd like to
与我合作，我想
thank everybody here everybody across
谢谢 大家这里所有人
the community that's been contributing
一直在贡献的社区
we have thousands of submissions coming
我们有成千上万的提交
in for deep traffic and I'm just truly
对于深度交通，我只是真的
humbled by the support we've been
受到我们支持的谦卑
getting and the team behind this class
获得和这个班级背后的团队
is incredible thank you to Nvidia Google
非常感谢Nvidia Google
Amazon Alexa auto live in Toyota and
亚马逊Alexa 自动 生活在丰田和
today we have shirts extra large extra
今天我们有额外的额外衬衫
extra large medium over there small and
超大的 媒介在那里小 和
large over there the big and small
大大小小的那边
people over here and then the
人们在这里然后
medium-sized people over here so just
这里只是中等规模的人
grab it grab one and enjoy thank you
抓住它抓住 一个，谢谢你
very much
非常
[Applause]
[掌声]